# Yuki Matsuno Data Scientist









Japanese Data Scientist with expertise in data analysis using **Python**, **pandas**, and **machine/deep learning** models. I am excited by the incredible power of data science to make things possible that are impossible for humans. I am particularly interested in machine learning/deep learning, and CNN.

# **Professional Experience**

2019 – present Tokyo	<ul> <li>Technical Support Specialist, Pearson Vue Co Ltd.</li> <li>Conduct technical troubleshooting on test servers via phone/remote control within the required SLA time</li> <li>Configuration or install software for front-end users who require assistance</li> <li>Program management, translating client guides, technical issue escalation</li> </ul>
2019 Tokyo	<ul> <li>Network Infrastructure Engineer, Outsourcing Technology Co. Ltd</li> <li>Managing Interactive Voice Response systems (IVR)</li> <li>Mass scale DDI migration of telecom numbers in event of relocation</li> </ul>
2018 – 2019	Working Holiday, Government of Canada

### **Data Science Projects**

**Crop classifier [App □ ], [Code □ ]** 

Developed a machine learning classifier to help mill owners optimize agribusiness by classifying satellite image files as rice or sugarcane

Dataset size: 9000+ satellite imagery

Method: KNN model, data engineering, pipeline (scaler, PCA), Confusion Matrix

#### **E-commerce Service Optimization**

Analysis for better customer experience and to maximize e-commerce company's profits. Gave a presentation.

Dataset size: 100k orders

Method: data frame creation, Statsmodels, OLS, visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn)

#### **Education**

2021	<ul> <li>LeWagon 6 Month Data Science Bootcamp, LeWagon Tokyo</li> <li>Received Special mention during LeWagon [Demo Day ☑]. [Demo ☑], [Code ☑]</li> <li>Learnt Machine Learning, Data Science, Python, SQL, Git, GitHub, Heroku</li> <li>Short Certifications: Ruby Foundations, Data Science Foundations</li> </ul>	
2009 – 2014	<ul> <li>Bachelor of English and Literature, Prefectural University of Kumamoto</li> <li>GPA of 3.9 / 5, worked as freelance translator during and after university</li> <li>Exchange Student to Montana State University, USA for 1 year</li> </ul>	

## **Data Science Skills**

Data Mining	<b>Machine Learning</b>	<b>Data Engineering</b>	Cloud DevOps
Web Scraping, APIs,	Scikit-learn,	Python, SQL,	Heroku, GCP, Docker,
Python	TensorFlow, Pandas,	algorithms (KNN,	Git, Packaging Code
	Matplotlib, Python	Random Forest, SVM,	
		CNN, SGD)	